[guitar riff intro]
Hi, I'm Matt!
And I'm Tom!
And I'm Tim!
TOM: And this is the park bench.
The light is fading, and I've still got hay fever.
MATT: He always says the light is
fading when the light is fading.
You can tell that the light is fading cause
you know we record many in one go.
TOM: But,
...we have one more story to
tell with Tim here on the bench.
TOM: And the tale-
TIM: No one told-
TOM: Yeah we- well, I didn't warn you about this,
...but this is the tale of the second greatest
prank I've ever pulled in my life.
MATT: [gasp] OOOOHHHH
TIM: Ooohh, that one, yeah.
TOM: That's-
TIM: Yeah.
TOM: I'm going to preface this
...with saying that I've previously gone on record on-
...of saying I don't particularly like pranks.
Uh, I certainly don't like YouTube
prank channels and all that.
'cuz my...
My requirements for a good prank is th-
Uh... it should not affect
...health or family or career.
TIM: Mhmm.
TOM: Uh, it should always have the ability to opt-out.
TOM: Y- You shou- You should be able to-
TIM: Yeah.
TOM: ...to say,
"Okay, yeah. No. That's not- that's not for me,"
Even if you don't know you're doing that,
You should have- be able to have that reaction.
TIM: Mmm.
TOM: And this was borderline on the second,
...but it was too good an opportunity to pass up.
TIM: Mhmm.
While we're at a point like that,
...I really need to cough. Is that ok?
TOM: I mean yeah, we're gonna keep the cough in.
TIM: [cough cough]
TOM: Uh, okay. Fair enough.
TOM: So-
TIM: [cough]
TOM: Tha- That's Tim coughing.
TIM: That's me coughing.
TOM: Yeah.
TIM: Sorry, thing in my throat.
TOM: Um...
[clears throat]
Why- why don't you tell it from your perspective, Tim?
Just th- Just the first bit.
'Cuz it went downhill after.
TIM: [laugh]
TOM: Well, I overcommitted.
TIM: You know, I-
TIM: Well, yeah.
I got a...
...call on my phone,
Um, it was from a blocked number.
TOM: Yep.
TIM: And...
I- I answered it 'cuz, you know,
I-
Some people don't answer phone calls,
I'd- I will answer any phone call 'cuz I get
...lonely and I like people talking to me.
MATT, TOM: [laughs]
TIM: Umm...
TIM: And-
TOM: He's on Twitter, folks!
MATT, TIM: [laughs]
TIM: Umm...
Uh... Yes, and the voice,
I didn't really get a chance to say much
because the first thing I heard was,
"Hi..."
"Hi, Tim."
"This is you calling"
"...from the future."
"Whatever you do,"
"...it's really important that you don't."
And then it cut dead.
Oh, it's an unknown number,
I have no idea what I've heard
...and it was my voice!
I don't... know-
I didn't know what to think.
TIM: Uh-
TOM: 'Cuz you used-
TOM: You used to do university radio, like-
TOM: ...and you know what your voice sounds like.
TIM: And- Yeah. And well yeah,
TIM: ...it wasn't like 'the-voice-in-my-head' my voice.
It was... my voice!
And I...
...got a bit weirded out.
And then I went on Twitter
...and had something of a breakdown.
MATT, TIM: [laughs]
TOM: So, let's skip back 15 minutes.
TOM: I'm in a pub.
MATT: [laughs]
TOM: And I can't remember which
pub it was or where it was,
...but I was talking to someone and I was like,
"Oh!"
"Tim's here, that's a coincidence."
"That's not Tim!"
It is a perfect sound-alike for Tim
...to the extent where there were like two or
three times during 5 minutes where I went,
"Is that Tim- No it's not."
It was just this guy who had Tim's voice.
Accent, pitch, intonation, speech patterns, everything.
MATT: And in the nicest possible way,
...you do have a very unique voice.
TIM: Yeah, okay.
MATT: So this- this was...
MATT: ...just calling out.
TOM: He wasn't doing a impression,
...it was just perfect.
MATT: I wasn't there.
So I did the only possible thing in those circumstances,
MATT, TIM: [laughs]
TOM: ...recognize what an opportunity this was,
TOM: ...walked up to this man and said,
"Hi. You have the same voice as my friend."
"If I call him up,"
"...can you read this to him?"
ALL: [laughs]
TOM: And he said yes.
MATT, TIM: [laughs]
TOM: So, um, I think-
[clears throat]
I can't remember his name now,
I should've looked that up,
cuz i know that it is somewhere.
I- I've said this to him many many times,
"Thank you."
MATT, TIM: [laughs]
TOM: ...because Tim then-
So what I'm doing is I'm- I-
TOM: 'Cuz I know you'll tweeting about it,
TIM: Mhmm.
TOM: ...as I'm checking.
TOM: Is what-
'Cuz I'm wondering what Tim is going to say.
And in the event you are having
a serious freak-out about this,
TOM: I'm immediately going to call you,
TIM: Mhmm.
TOM: ...explain what was going on,
...and get that guy back on the phone,
...to cle- to clear things up.
TIM: And, as I recall it,
TIM: ...'cuz I did have a breakdown,
TOM: Yeah.
TIM: I was like...
...so-
TIM: ...all capital letters:
MATT, TOM: [laughs]
TIM: ...etc. etc. etc.
And then I think,
...if you're like- you were about to call me,
...but then i posted:
"Actually if this- if this is a joke,"
"...please don't tell me,"
...because I want to think it's happening."
TOM: Now that is, what we call in the business,
...an explicit opt in.
MATT, TIM: [laughs]
TOM: And what you said was-
[coughs]
'Cuz we, uh...
We actually set a date-
We actually set a date about how long in the future
TIM: Ooh.
TOM: ...that you're calling you from.
TOM: And...
...you said,
"Please don't tell me, cuz I want to believe"
"...that on that date,"
"...I'm going to be making a call back to myself."
Well, now I've got a challenge.
MATT: [laughs]
TOM: In the meantime, this must have been about-
You were going off with Tim somewhere,
...'cuz I asked you, Matt,
...to ask him how he was feeling about it.
That it would g-
This was Eurovision!
This was the year after Eurovision, it must have been.
Three years ago-
TIM: Yes, it could have been, yeah, 'cuz it was arou-
TIM: It was around about May or something.
MATT: It was.
TIM: No, it ca-
MATT: I know it was revealed when
we were all in a train together.
MATT: The three of us were on a train together.
TOM: No, no, it wasn't.
no, no it wasn't, it was revealed at a-
oh I- we'll get to that, no it wasn't, no you two
TOM: Y- you two were on a train
or a plane or something-
MATT: I know you needed some information,
MATT: ...and I was able to provide you with that info.
TIM: [laughs]
TOM: I needed to know that
Tim was doing okay with this,
...was not massively freaking out.
So I let Matt in on what had happened,
...and asked him to check that Tim was okay by
...asking in conversation what that was about.
MATT: 'Cuz I had seen it on Twitter like...
I get a text from Tom and I'm like,
"Oh, of course."
[laughs]
TIM: So yeah, that's the first time you found out, right?
MATT: [laughs] Yeah.
[laughs]
TOM: 'Cuz, let's be honest,
...if anyone in this friends group
is going to pull a stunt like that,
...it's probably going to be me.
TIM: Yep. [laughs]
MATT: [laughs]
TIM: And that's why we love being friends with you.
[laughs]
TOM: So what, uh- what-
What was that like, what did-
Do you remember that conversation at all?
MATT: Not really, but I do remember asking him like,
"W- what happened there?"
Getting him to tell 'cuz i didn't know the details.
TOM: Yeah.
MATT: Um...
MATT: And he described the whole lot
MATT: ...and you s-
TIM: Probably ended up with something like,
"I don't really know, I guess..."
"...I'll see what happens on..."
TIM: "...May the whatever."
MATT: And you had a little giddy
...'hehe' in your eyes.
MATT: [laughs]
TOM: So I have to try to make this real
In hindsight,
...what I should have done
...was call you with the wrong number,
...got a sample of your voice
saying "Hello" and recorded it,
...and played that back.
What I actually did was I bought a burner mobile phone,
...loaded it with one number
...that I had set up that speci-
That was in an area code somewhere
in the middle of nowhere.
And I had set that up
...so that when THAT specific phone
...called THAT specific number
...at the time
...that had been written, handwritten
...by someone else,
(so it didn't have my handwriting)
...in a package
...that I put through his letterbox,
TIM: Hmm.
TOM: ...by getting his address from Matt...
MATT and TIM: [laughs]
TOM: ...only at that time
...would it play a series of weird tones and noises and-
TIM: Did you actually do- what- that's-
TIM: That's really incredible- a lot of effort-
TOM: Because I know-
TOM: And it only worked once!
Because I know you called that back,
TIM: I did call that back-
TOM: And what happened then?
TIM: I said those exact words that had been said to me.
TOM: Yes.
TOM: And-
TIM: And, uh, and-
TOM: And completed the- the causal loop.
TIM: Yeah, and that was okay and I was... fine,
I thought nothing more of it,
...until a few days later.
no a hang on, can I just say the- the other thing,
Did you call that number again?
no I didn't I only called it once.
which is great, because you were actually respecting the laws of time travel there
yeah exactly I thought that I got- I know it's stupid (if you hadn't respected the laws of time travel there) if I had called myself again,
well I haven't called myself again, so I can't call myself again, because I don't know, is this pre-determination or ...
If you had, it would have played a message asking you about your payment protection insurance.
which, for those outside of the U.K., has been spam phone calls that people have been getting for years now
it would have asked you about that
and it only worked once, and it only worked in a 5 minute window, and it only worked from that one phone number number
and it- yes! and you completed the loop
which was amazing
it's funny because i didn't even know his address until two weeks before when we went through the eurovision entries
I hadn't been to your house yet, didn't know where you lived, I had to find your address on streetview
and you couldn't quite remember it, but you knew the street- uhh you moved from there now right?
I have moved from there.
you knew the street, and you knew it had a bay window, and some- and a super soaker- a water pistol in the
I saw, it's on that street, it's got a water pistol and a bay window.
This is a big water pistol, it was worth having on display (IT'S THAT ONE! it's that one. it's fine. goes in.)
several weeks later, uh, we got free tickets to a show by one of (IT WAS it was West End Boys) yeah someone gave us
fly, sorry
um, someone gave us free tickets to uh uh the
surrounded by midges all over
basically loads of washed up popstars from a while back (that's harsh, that's harsh)
It had Matt Willis in it, who at that point before "McBusted" so at that point
um, doing singing songs from West End numbers basically
which- which absolutely makes sense as a show, anywhere but the west end.
where you can go and see the original show.
uh at one point I asked you about it
you- I'm- I don't know
and, uh, and I didn't know what to do. should I- i figured i couldn't slap you cuz you know, we're in public, there are a lot of people in close proximity
so I thought that wouldn't go down so well
so I think I just looked at you and ... with a sense of, I can't remember if it was hatred or loathing, or one of those two
but for a little while you were time travelling
for a little while I was time travelling, and I was happy with that, and do you know, I still tell that story to this day.
and- a- there is- there is one other thing that someone brought up to me, and I forget who it was, it was someone I talked to at a conference a year or so ago and talked about this.
and he said that all sensible, it all makes sense
but if you read time travel fiction, you read all this that the most sensible timeline, is one where time travel is never invented.
because it keeps resetting it's self, it keeps resetting it's self, until time travel doesn't happen, and that's now a consistent universe.
and if that were to happen (oh I se- oh right yes ok) the time travel, someone goes back, changes a thing, someone goes back, and keeps going
until time travel is never invented at which point you've got a universe that doesn't change anymore.
and he said, well he's a science fiction writer and if that ever happened, surely there would be all sorts of little things left over
that would need a reeeally unlikely explanation- explanation to happen
like someone accidentally stumbling into someone who happens to be an exact voice match
with the one person who happens to be able to technically pull that off
and that would be the type of debris left over from a time travel accident
so your view is that despite having being the one who pulled that off, time travel still happened.
i'm saying you can believe that. (ok)
and to be fair ... you deserved it
I deserved it- it was fine I- I don't know what you mean by that, but over all I enjoyed it looking back at it in hindsight
(i was happy it happened) Good. Good i'm glad you are, because that's the mark of it all ... yeah.
I'm referencing a prank from a few years previous that we have talked about before on this bench.
what was that?
was this a prank that I- OH yes that one.
oh ... yeah
he got you back now
oh man I haven't even thought!
I said "can I have a- can I uh take a nomination form to be president please?" and uh she said "yeah, absolutely! what's the name?"(put mad captain tom down)
I said "Tom Scott" "what's the Email?" "uudududu"
In all these years Tim, I've never really thought of that as payback
I thought you owed me one, and you know what?
I'm happy with that! let's consider that loop closed as well.
BWAAAAAAMMMM [guitar riff ending]
do I get to ask you about the biggest prank you ever played?
no
no? ok.
but that's a good bit for after the camera